# ABRIEL DAVILA RONTEND WEB





🏫 630-864-0607 | 🔀 gdavila0819@gmail.com | 🖨 <u>gabedavila.com</u> | -





github.com/GabrielJDavila

## PROFILE

I am a qualified and professional frontend developer with 3 years of programming experience and working with clients. Creatively driven with an endless curiosity, I use my skills to create high-quality applications with a great user experience. I am continuously learning and developing my skills further while seeking meaningful work to create a positive impact.

## EXPERIENCE

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER

Freelance

May 2021 - Present

- Website and web application creation for small businesses in Illinois.
- Utilized ReactJS, React Router, Firebase, JS, CSS, and HTML
- Other tools/skills: Git/GitHub Desktop, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Bootstrap, APIs, JSON, UX/UI design

#### **FITNESS COACH**

H<sub>4</sub> Training

Feb 2020 - present

- Provided outstanding customer service and experience.
- Designed fitness programming for clients, provided nutrition coaching, and trained groups of 4-8 people in a fast-paced environment.
- Wrote articles, kept website content maintained, and created social media content for high-end studio.

## PERSONAL TRAINER

Self-employed

Nov 2016 - Jan 2023

- Trained clients in multiple settings; studios, commercial gyms, in-home, and online.
- Provided clients with fitness programming and nutrition guidelines.
- Handled social media marketing, blog content creation, and website development for my own business.

## SKILLS

- ReactJS
- Visual Studio Code
- React Router
- Figma
- Javascript
- UX/UI Design
- CSS
- Wireframing
- HTML5
- Bootstrap
- Firebase
- **APIs**
- Git/Github
- JSON

## PROJECT SAMPLES

#### H4 Team Notes App: Live | GitHub

- Team notes app for fitness studio. Users can sign up and login, create/update/delete notes. and add clients to the database.
- Tools: React Router, Firebase, HTML, CSS

### M&G Clean Pros Budget Tracker: Live | GitHub

- Budget tracker built for a small cleaning business. Add/delete income & expenses, and a dashboard renders total income, expenses, and profits.
- Tools: React Router, Firebase, HTML, CSS

# EDUCATION/CERTS

**COLLEGE:** Waubonsee Community College Associate of Kinesiology August 2014 - 2016

TEAM TREEHOUSE FRONTEND TRACK

May 2021 - November 2022

SCRIMBA FRONTEND BOOTCAMP

January 20, 2023 - October 16, 2023

# REFERENCES

Hank Ebeling - Owner of H4 Training LLC | 630-244-0536 | h4training@gmail.com

Marie Alvarez - Owner of M&G Clean Pros LLC | 630-642-3773 | mgcleanpros@gmail.com

Jen Heggaton - Fltness Cooridinator, Wyndemere Senior Center | 630-347-1258 | heggatonjennifer@wyndemerelcs.com